# RAMDHAN AKBAR BAKHAR

Telepon : 0812-8400-0413

Email : akbarbakhar@gmail.com

: www.linkedin.com/in/RamdhanAB LinkedIn

### PROFILE\_

I am a professional with 5 years of experience in the field of Supply Chain Management Systems Analyst. I am used to analyzing and identifying opportunities, improvements and increasing efficiency in work, familiar with SAP MB51, MB52 and MIGO as well as collaborating with purchasing and logistics warehouse teams to achieve performance targets precisely.

I have strong analytical skills and the ability to work well in a team and individually. Apart from that, I have high discipline so I received the best employee award in a multinational company. With a strong background and commitment to good and quality results, I am ready to contribute to your company.

#### WORKING EXPERIENCE \_\_\_\_\_

PT. POSCO DX Indonesia - Cilegon Supply Chain Management Analyst System

August 2019 - July 2024

Responsibility:

- Provide technical support and guidance to manufacturing personnel and other stakeholders to ensure smooth and efficient SCM operations.
- Manage the transportation system for procurement of goods or carriers and transportation for sending domestic and export
- Manage the layout of ready-to-ship products
- Manage transportation for product movement between warehouses
- Manage the bidding system for car, train and ship transportation vendors.
- Analyze and evaluate management system progress to identify opportunities for improvement and increased efficiency.
- Collaborate with IT and other stakeholders to create new business.
- Work with cross-functional teams to ensure that SCM systems are aligned with business needs and objectives.
- Ensure the SCM flow is integrated with other systems and processes, such as SAP, ERP and MES

PT. Sumber Alfaria trijaya, Tbk - Serang

Marketing Design & Warehouse

January 2019 - July 2019

Responsibility:

- Manage the receipt of goods from suppliers to the warehouse and arrange delivery transportation from the warehouse to the
- Create a stock list of goods and inventory in the warehouse
- Create promotional designs and event product layout guides for stores

PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia, Tbk - Serang

QA Staff

August 2015 - November 2016

Responsibility:

- Provides frontliner service standard scores (CS, Teller)
- Create a standard service simulation schedule
- Checking the completeness of banking standards
- Ensure everything goes according to SOP
- Provide standard appearance scores for Branch Offices, Units as well as their equipment in accordance with banking standards
- Input assessment results into the internal audit system
- Create QA data reports for internal audit needs

#### SKILL AND LANGUAGE \_\_\_\_\_

- Data Analytics
- Supply Chani Management
- Marketing Administration
- English
- Korean



# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

## PERSONAL DATA

Full Name : Ramdhan Akbar Bakhar Place, Date of birth : Bandung, 20 March 1991

Gender : Male
Citizenship : Indonesia
Religion : Islam
Status : Married

Address : Jl. Raya SMAN 1 Kramatwatu No. 3 Rt 07 Rw 14 Subdistric Kramatwatu

Province Banten

Telephone : 0812-8400-0413

Email : akbarbakhar@gmail.com

### FORMAL EDUCATION

1. SD Negeri 2 Serang	: Year 1997	- 2003
2. SMP Negeri 47 Bandung	: Year 2003	- 2006
3. SMA Negeri 4 Kota Serang	: Year 2006	- 2009
4. Universitas Serang Raya (S1- Informatics Engineering)	: Year 2011	- 2015

### **CERTIFICATES AND AWARDS**

1. Computer Courses [MS OFFICE]	: Year 2009
2. Training on Operation and Maintenance Networks for 20 Kv	: Year 2010
3. President Director Award [Best Employee]	: Year 2020

# WORK HISTORY

1. Technician at PT. Mahiza Karya Mandir	: Year 2011	- 2013
2. Staff Adm Technician at PT. Mahiza Karya Mandiri	: Year 2013	- 2014
3. Coordinator Technician at PT. Mahiza Karya Mandiri	: Year 2014	- 2015
4. QA Satff at PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia	: Year 2015	- 2016
5. FS (Funds and Services) at PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia	: Year 2016	- 2017
6. AAO (Asociate Account Officer) di PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia	: Year 2017	- 2018
7. Marketing Design & Warehouse at PT. Sumber Alfaria Trijaya Tbk	: Year 2019	- 2019
8. Supply Chain Management Analyst System at PT. POSCO DX Indonesia	: Year 2019	- 2024

That's the life story I've made for the truth.

Serang, July 2024

Ramdhan Akbar Bakhar

